Edwin Roldan Delgado

2160 Charles Street, DuPont, Washington 706-955-6273 edwin.roldan2@gmail.com https://www.mrrolbot.com

Summary

Versatile Systems Engineer with over 12 years of cross-functional leadership in implementation, validation and deployment of large complex systems. Exceptional knowledge of a variety of Windows and Linux information systems. Well-versed in large-scale deployments, migrations and data storage solutions. Highly motivated, self-taught developer. Familiar with development and deployment process for many web-based technologies.

Skills

Linux, PowerShell, Python, JavaScript, Web Development, Web Design, ReactJS, Node.js, Spring Boot, AWS, Git, GitHub, Docker, Databases, SQL, Java, CI/CD

Experience

Information Systems Engineer

U.S. Army Joint Base Lewis-McChord, Washington

10/2021 - Present

- Senior SASMO Chief managing over 400 STAMIS systems across JBLM.
- Responsible for providing both client system, hardware, and software technical support, as well as
 upgrades to all customers within JBLM, to include Combat Service support Automated Information
 System Interface (CAISI), and Very Small Aperture Satellite (VSAT) and Global Combat Support System
 Army (GCSS-A).
- Set-up, configure, and install software updates and approved images and fielding of new systems and equipment.
- Automate data collection activities to increase productivity with PowerShell.

Information Systems Engineer

U.S. Army Joint Base Lewis-McChord, Washington

10/2018 - 10/2021

- Responsible for designing and creating network systems and databases to process information for an Air Defense Battalion.
- Maintain the stability and navigation of networks to ensure their security and prevent unauthorized access and illegal data dissemination.
- Developed and implemented a robust Network Infrastructure with a combination of Ultra High Frequency, Internet Protocol, Troposcatter, and SATCOM systems.
- Maintained stability, integrity and efficient operation of information systems supporting organizational functions.

Cyber Network Defender

U.S. Army Fort Carson, Colorado

09/2015 - 01/2018

- Conduct real time threat and vulnerability assessments through the use of ACAS, ESM, Host Based Security systems, Security Onion, and Snort.
- Handled scripting tasks for debugging and automation using Python.
- Incident response and Blue Team
- Developed Information Assurance policies and technical mitigation countermeasures to maximize network and information systems confidentiality, integrity, and availability.
- Additional duties as a Sysadmin for 18 servers to include: Domain Controllers, Exchange, SharePoint, SQL, WSUS, SCCM, Adobe Connect, and more.

Information Systems Technician

U.S. Army Fort Hood, Texas

03/2012 - 08/2015

- Help Desk Supervisor
- Set-up, configure, and install software updates and approved images and fielding of new systems and equipment.
- · Network Administrator, configured network hardware such as servers, routers, and switches.
- Maintained Combat Service support Automated Information System Interface (CAISI), and Very Small Aperture Satellite (VSAT)
- Battalion COMSEC Manager

Information Technology Specialist

U.S. Army Kandahar , Kandahar

01/2011 - 01/2012

- Enterprise Level Help Desk Technician over 20k customers.
- Used ticketing systems to manage and process support actions and requests.
- Active Directory & Group Policy Management
- SharePoint Manager
- Local Area Network (LAN) Manger

Education

B.S. Network Operations & Security

Western Governors University • Salt Lake City, Utah 77 Completed Credits